Igor Soloydenko

Sr. Software Engineer helping businesses doing the right things the right way. Problem identification; user-centrism; performance & tool mastership.

SUMMARY

Looking for a full-stack developer role which will put my 12 years of experience near developers focusing on Al-based project. Together with my expertise in front-end and microservice development we will reveal the full strength of the service or the product, thus building up the momentum of the business.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Time & Labor project for FAS (City of Seattle) • Palador • Senior Software Developer, Aug 2016 — Present

- Helped migrating to sprint-based development process from rigid spec-and-deadline based one.
- Implemented front-end solution and helped defining required APIs for several workstreams.
- Mentored team members on front-end development with Angular, micro-service development with ASP.NET Core (WebAPI), design and development best practices.
- Established patterns for RESTful approach to micro-service APIs.
- Improved Angular 2 development infrastructure by enabling Jasmine + Karma unit testing, and Protractor end-to-end testing.
- Implemented client-side logging platform.

M☆☆☆☆ (Confidential project) • Palador • Senior Software Developer, Feb 2016 — Aug 2016

- Designed and developed a low-latency messaging micro-service using MS Azure Service Fabric and SignalR.

Project Dashboard for Seattle Department of Transportation • Palador • Senior Software Developer, Oct 2015 — Feb 2016

- Built several features end-to-end (UI, RESTful services, persistence layer) and delivered project two weeks ahead of ETA.

Data Pipeline • Amazon Web Services • Software Development Engineer, Oct 2013 — Oct 2015

- Simplified Data Pipeline creation UX that significantly increased number of active customers.
- Improved monitoring and debugging UX to reduce operational pain and decrease repair time.
- Implemented EMR roles migration wizard that painlessly moves accounts to an improved security model.
- Introduced user activity data collection, analysis and reporting for future data-driven improvements.

ICTLit — cognitive skills assessment instrument • National Training Foundation • Full-stack Developer, Feb 2010 — Sept 2013

- Defined project direction and requirements as a member of board of sociology, psychology and tech experts.
- Designed and developed the entire system including test results evaluation service (Bayesian probabilistic networks).
- Conducted try-out and full scale tests in Thailand; Armenia; Belarus; Tatarstan and Moscow (Russia).
- Organized adoption of Agile development practices; Deployed and configured development infrastructure.

SCAN - System for Complex Analysis of News and Media • Interfax Group • Web Developer, Jun 2009 — Jan 2010

- Improved archived news search and browsing experience. Resolved various browser compatibility issues.

QuickWells • GISware Integro • Software Developer, Jul 2007 — Jun 2009

- Designed and built a scripting engine subsystem for underwater drilling CAD.

UES • Vigour a.s. • Software Developer, Aug 2006 – Jun 2007

- Contributed to developing widget library for corporate CMS.

Front-end

EMUS • Vigour a.s. • Software Developer, Feb 2006 - Aug 2006

- Improved performance of operational risks evaluation system by making structural changes in the database layer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Back-end ASP.NET Core (WebAPI), Node.js Angular, NgRx, RxJs, HTML, CSS, JS, TS Cloud Services AWS: EC2, RDS, DynamoDB, IAM, Data Pipeline

Azure: Logic Apps, Service Fabric

Testing xUnit, NSubstitute, Jasmine, Protractor, Karma Other Bash, Python, Auth0, MongoDB, MS SQL, MySQL

EDUCATION

Computer Science MS Degree Moscow State University of Instrument Engineering and Computer Sciences (MGUPI), 2003 — 2008

LANGUAGES

English, Russian, Romanian